International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Umhey, Frederick F., Executive Secretary. Correspondence, 1934-1955 [bulk 1940-1950]. 5780/005.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- I. Executive Secretary correspondence.
  - Reports on Charitable Institutions: 1947-52., Requests for financial aid. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Requests, 1936-1949.
    - Index for Years: 1936-49. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - A-B. Includes American Red Cross (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - C. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - D-E. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - F-G. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - H-I. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - J-L. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - M-N. (Box 28, Folder 9--10)
    - O-R. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - S. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - T-Z. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Retirement Fund
    - 1946-5, correspondence concerning retirement plans for Union members. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - 1948-54., Re staff retirement, Includes reports. (Box 29, Folder 5a-5b)
    - Staff-Trust agreements. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Reciprocity. 1951-53. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Coat and Suit Industry.
      - Rules and regulations, by-laws, and reports. 1943-54. (Box 30, Folder 1a-1b)
      - Listings of bonds, investments. 1950-56. (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence re investments, sale of municipal bonds (portfolio). 1952. (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Schlesinger and Bloom. 1951-53. (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Minutes. Dec. 1953, Nov. 1954. (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Minutes. Oct. 1952, Mar. 1953. May 1953. (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - June 1952, Aug. 13 and 20, 1952. (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - May 1952. (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - April 1952. (Two meetings) (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Minutes. Oct. 1951, Nov. 1951. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Securities: 1931-40. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - State Insurance Fund. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - St. Lawrence Seaway: 1941-54., correspondence bet. Umhey and U.S. officials re project. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Supplementary Death Benefit Fund: 1947-49. (Box 32, Folder 1a-1b)
  - Taft-Hartley Law: 1947-51., Includes bulletins issued by Union. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Tecklin (Alex) vs Dubinsky; 1947. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Trade Union Women's Advisory Committee (Women's Bureau): 1946. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Training Institute, ILGWU: 1949-53. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Unemployment insurance.
    - correspondence, reports issued by Research Department. 1941-54. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - 1934-40. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Advisory Council: 1945-53., Umhey representative of the NYS Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance. (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Advisory Council: 1940-43. (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Hughes-Brees Bill: 1953-54., Includes correspondence and reports. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Merit Rating: 1939-47. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - California, 1952.; New Jersey, 1950 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Union Health Center (Union Sanatorium Association, Inc.)
    - Correspondence with Dr. Leo Price (Director), reports.: 1940-54. (Box 33, Folder 4a-4c)
    - Correspondence on negotiating agreements with Building Service Employees International Union. 1949. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, committee minutes, reports to the GEB from the UHC Committee. 1951-54. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Committee minutes. 1947-50. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Committee minutes. 1940-46. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Reports. 1940-48. (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Financial and budget reports. Dec. 1951-54. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Financial and budget reports. Jan-Nov. 1951. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Financial and budget reports. 1945-50. (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence re Cooperative Health Federation of America. 1948-50. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Examination and exhibits re fire claim (275 Seventh Ave.). 1949-51. (Box 34, Folder 7a-7b)
    - Expansion program. 1945. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Incorporation papers, by-laws and related legal matters. 1917-51. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Office Employees international Union, Local 153. Labor Contracts: 1951-55. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Labor Contracts: 1946-55, Nurses and Technicians Guild, Local 312 of OEIU. Examination and exhibits re fire claim (275 Seventh Ave.). (Box 35, Folder 4a-4b)
    - Lay Staff Matters: 1940, 1945-54., Includes correspondence with Pauline Newman. (Box 35, Folder 5a-5b)
    - 1939-48., Local Union matters. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Management Matters: 1945-49. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Newark Health Center: 1949-54. (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Optical Department; 1945-48. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Publicity: 1949-51. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Sick benefits. 1952-53. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Renting matters. 1945-49. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Research memoranda (prepared by James Lipsig). 1946-48. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Reports. 1951-52 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Union Label Trades Department (AFL): 1936-53. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Union Labor Life Insurance Co. (U.L.L.I.), Correspondence, investment Committee minutes, stockholders' meetings, executive Committee meetings, financial statements, reports.
    - 1954 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - 1953. (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - 1952. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - 1951 (Box 37, Folder 5a-5b)
    - 1950. (Box 37, Folder 6a-6b)
    - 1949. (Box 38, Folder 1a-1c)
    - 1947-48. (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - 1945-46. (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Death Benefit Claims. 1951-52. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Mortgage Committee: 1945-53., Correspondence and meeting minutes. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - United Housing Foundation: 1952-55., Includes correspondence, minutes, releases, publications on ILGWU housing projects. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - United Housing Foundation: 1945-52. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Union Broadcasting Corporation of California, KFMV:
    - General data. 1949-51. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - correspondence with Cliff Gill (Station Director), reports. 1949-51. (Box 39, Folder 4a-4b)
    - 1948. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - 1945-46. (Box 39, Folder 6a-6b)
    - Associated Press and Associated Program Service. 1948. (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence on closing and selling station. 1951-52. (Box 40, Folder 2a-2b)
    - Edison Co. of Southern Calif.: 1948., Agreement with company on selling energy to station. (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Federal Communications Commission: 1950-51., correspondence (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - FCC: 1949. (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - FCC: 1948. (Box 40, Folder 6a-6b)
    - FCC: 1946-47. (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Agreement with International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 45. 1949. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, legal records. 1947-51. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Personnel Applications: 1946-48. (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Programming: 1948-51. (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Publicity and Pictures. (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Site and Property Matters: 1949. (Box 41, Folder 6a-6b)
    - Site and Property Matters: 1947-48. (Box 41, Folder 7a-7b)
    - Staff Matters: 1948-51. (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Water System: 1948. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Union Broadcasting Corporation of California, KWIK.
    - General data. 1949-52. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Closing of Station: 1950-52. (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Federal Communications Commission: 1949-51. (Box 42, Folder 3a-3c)
    - Legal records. 1946-53. (Box 42, Folder 4a-4b)
  - Unity Broadcasting Corporation of Massachusetts.
    - General matters. 1948-49, 1952-55. (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Federal Communications Commission: 1947, 1956. (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Legal records. 1945-55. (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Personnel applications (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re property site. 1945-50. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Unity Broadcasting Corporation of Missouri:
    - General correspondence. 1945-52. (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Closing of station. 1952. (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Federal Communications Commission: 1946-48. (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Property and Site: 1946-56. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Unity Broadcasting Corporation of New Jersey: 1945-47. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Unity Broadcasting Corporation of New York, WFDR
    - 1940-53., Includes correspondence on exhibits (2b). (Box 44, Folder 2a-2b)
    - American Federation of Radio Artists: 1949-51., Correspondence on negotiations for agreement. (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers: 1949, 1952., Correspondence on negotiations for agreements. (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - American Telephone and Telegraph: 1949. (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Associated Press: 1949-52. (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Associated Program Service: 1949-52. (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Closing and lease agreement. 1952, 1955. (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Federal Communications Commission: 1946-52. (Box 44, Folder 9a-9c)
    - Inaugural Broadcast: June 16, 1949. (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Inaugural Broadcast: June 1949., Includes congratulatory messages. (Box 45, Folder 1a-1b)
    - Inaugural Broadcast: June 1949., Lists of people invited. (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Inaugural Broadcast: June 1949, Scripts (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Publicity: 1949. (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 1212; correspondence on negotiations for agreement. 1948-51. (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Legal Papers: 1949-51. (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Programs: 1945-50. (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Telephone: 1949. (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - WCFM contract agreement with WFDR. 1949. (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Docket No. 7228; Exhibit No. 14. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Unity Broadcasting Corporation of Pennsylvania:
    - 1945-48, 1957. (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Federal Communications Commission; 1946-48., Correspondence (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Legal Records: 1946-52. (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Personnel Applications. (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Property Site: 1946. (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Docket No. 7643; Exhibit No. 4., n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Unity Broadcasting Corporation of Tennessee, WVUN.
    - Correspondence, 1949-51, 1954-55. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - 1946-48. (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - American Federation of Radio Artists and American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers on negotiations for agreement. 1948-51. (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Associated Press and Associated Program Service on negotiations of agreement. 1948-51. (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Closing of Stations: 1948-54. (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Federal Communications Commission: 1950-51., Correspondence (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - FCC: 1948-49., Correspondence (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - FCC: 1945-47. (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Insurance: 1949-56. (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 662, on negotiation of agreements. 1948-51. (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Legal Records: 1945-51, 1955-56. (Box 48, Folder 4a-4b)
    - Novik, Morris: 1948-51. (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Pictures and Publicity: 1948-50. (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Programs: 1948. (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Property Site: 1946-49, 1951-53. (Box 49, Folder 1a-1c)
    - Reports and related correspondence. 1948-50. (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Staff Matters: 1947-50. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Unity Broadcasting Corporation of Tennessee, WAPO (Chattanooga), 1948 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Unity Broadcasting Corporation of Tennessee, WCFM: 1949. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Unity House.
    - 1946-54. (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Attorneys (Ellenberger and Edwards, Pa.): 1934-49. (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Banks: 1934-46. (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and Committee minutes. 1945-55. (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Complaints: 1935-42. (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Financial reports. 1945-53 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Official opening. 1941-53. (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Personal Injury Claims: 1935-53 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Philadelphia Building: 1945-47. (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Rates, circulars, printed material. (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Veterans: 1945-48., correspondence on aid and rehabilitation to veterans. (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Veterans, Committee on Veterans Affairs: 1946 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - World War II
    - General Correspondence: 1941-44, Includes letters from Adjutant General's office to proceed to Washington for duty in the Readjustment Division, Production Division or Purchase Division (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - War Contracts and Orders
      - Correspondence re contracts and government orders for Army uniforms. 1941-44. (Box 51, Folder 2a-2d)
      - Correspondence from locals re war orders or curtailment problems. 1941-43. (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Bulletins from Union Research Department and announcement of contracts. (Box 51, Folder 4a-4b)
      - Raincoats, 1942., Includes correspondence with Mayor F.H. LaGuardia of N.Y.C. (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Standard Knitting Mills, 1941. (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Walsh-Healy Bill on Public Contracts, 1938. (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Newspaper clippings. 1942. (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - War Department Amortization Branch: 1941-45., Memoranda. (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - War Labor Board: 1943-44. (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Gantner and Mattern vs ILGWU: 1939-46., correspondence with lawyers pertaining to case. (Box 52, Folder 6a-6c)
    - Gantner and Mattern vs ILGWU. (Box 52, Folder 7a-7b)
    - Legal record. (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Legislation
      - Correspondence not directly related to war, and David Dubinsky's statement before Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, 2-25-47. 1935-47. (Box 53, Folder 2a-2b)
      - Anti-Discrimination Bill: 1945 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Case Bill: 1946. (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - Homework: 1934-45. (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Minimum Wage Law: 1939-42., Umhey, member of Budget Advisory Committee (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board: 1940-42., correspondence and releases. (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - National Coat and Suit Ind. Recovery Board: 1941-45 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - National Labor Relations Board: 1938-39. (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Office of Price Administration: 1942-44., correspondence re 'MPR Regulation 287,' manufacturers' prices for women's, girls' and children's outerwear. (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Wage Adjustment for David Dubinsky and Umhey: 1943. (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Wage Adjustment, Staff: 1943-44. (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Wage and Hour Law
      - General correspondence. 1938-41 (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - Bulletins, printed material from Wage and Hour Division re women's apparel industry. 1941-42. (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - Bulletins from Union Research Department. 1938-47. (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - Wage-freezing regulations and local Union problems related to freeze. 1941-45. (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - Industry Committee and related legislative material on labor. 1940-42. (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - War Manpower Commission: 1942-45. (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - War Production Board
      - M388 (Section C setting priorities in the garment industry): 1945. (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Rayon and Silk Industry: 1941-43. (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Priorities (misc. material). 1941-42. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Wool Labor Advisory Committee: 1942-43. (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Workmen's Compensation, Moreland investigation: 1943-45. (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - With These Hands: 1949-53., correspondence on production and copyrights. (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - With These Hands, Movie Production: 1950-51., Re foreign rights. (Box 55, Folder 7)
- II. Personal correspondence.
  - Personal Records: 1954-55. (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Personal Recommendations
    - 1952-53. (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - 1950-51. (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - 1948-49. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - 1945-47. (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - 1934-40, 1927-28., Includes Letters from Morris Hillquit. (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - 1941-44. (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Umhey's Death: Jan. 1955. (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Frederick F. Umhey Fund (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Frederick F. Umhey House (Box 56, Folder 10)